# Victor K. Mithamo

## Introduction\_

I am a Software developer with over 6 years of programming experience. I have specialized in JavaScript and Typescript with knowledge in PHP and Java Spring boot as well. I understand Agile methodology in the software development life cycle. I have good experience with databases both SQL and No SQL and have worked with both Linux and cpanel based servers such as RHEL, Ubuntu, Arch and Cent OS.

## Skills\_

## **PROGRAMMING**

JavaScript • Typescript • NodeJS • ReactJS • React Native • PHP • WordPress • MySQL • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Tailwind • Ubuntu • RHEL • Cent OS • Apache2 • Nginx • Docker • Kubernetes • CI/CD • Java Spring Boot (Beginner)

#### Links\_

GitHub: Victor Mithamo in Linked In: Victor Mithamo

### **Education**

## KENYA METHODIST UNIVERSITY

BBA - FINANCE

Jul 2015 Second Class (Upper) ♥ Nairobi, Kenya

## KANJURI HIGH SCHOOL

KCSE

♥ Nyeri, Kenya

# **Certifications**

# **SPRING BOOT FOR BEGINNERS**

**AMIGOS CODE** 

🛗 April 2023

**♀** amigoscode.com

## Referees\_

# **LEVIS IRUNGU**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - DTB upon request

# **BILDAD KANURI**

Managing Director - Kanuri Limited upon request

# **NEERAJ KAMDAR**

Managing Director - Orrasis upon request

## Experience

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

DIAMOND TRUST BANK

**Aug** 2022 – Date

Nairobi, Kenya

- Develop Full Stack applications for different bank products using agile methodology and CI/CD pipelines to deploy to the cloud within Kubernetes.
- Develop and Deploy APIs via the banks ESB platform for third party consumption and registration of the APIs onto the gateway for public consumption.

## TALENT ACQUISITION CONSULTANT

AKEO AS

m Dec 2021 – May 2022

♥ Nairobi, Kenya

• I assisted Akeo AS(a startup in Nairobi) to outsource for Software Engineering Talent in Kenya for their new Kenyan subsidiary.

#### IT CONSULTANT & PROJECT MANAGER

Wakandi Group AS

Mar 2021 - May 2022

Nairobi, Kenya

- I played a role in the go-to-market for Wakandi's core banking platform with a key role in data acquisition and entry.
- Through the local partner Kanuri Limited, I took up the role of project manager, under which I oversaw the on-boarding of new partners onto the Wakandi-CAMS platform.
- As PM, I also worked with the development team in Wakandi to oversee updates to the CAMS platform based on client feedback collected in the field to ensure clear timelines and delivery.

# **LEAD PROGRAMMER**

SPOT THE BALL LIMITED

**#** Jul 2019 – Sep 2021

Nairobi, Kenya

- Developed and supported the gaming platform for Spot The Ball
- Lead in integrating to different MNO services such as Bulk SMS, USSD and Mpesa Apis.

## JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

ORRASIS LIMITED

# Jul 2017 - Jun 2019

Nairobi, Kenya

- Designed and developed websites for Orrasis clientelle using the WordPress CMS where we created custom themes and plugins for various client needs.
- · Data entry

### **BANK TELLER**

SMEP MICROFINANCE BANK

**I** Jun 2015 – Jun 2017

**♀** Nairobi, Kenya

 Perfomed bank teller services including cash management, OTC cross-selling, cheque and cash handling.

## **RETAIL BANKING INTERN**

SMEP MICROFINANCE BANK

Feb 2015 - Mar 2015

Nairobi, Kenya

 I performed Customer Service duties, Sales of bank products, assisted the credit team to prepare presentations for the branch credit committee.